Article starting on page 44.
Capability Building MCCIA Conducts Five-Day Agri-Food EXIM Certification Course MCCIA’s Agriculture Export Facilitation Centre (AEFC) conducted a five-day AgriFood EXIM Management Certification Course from August 17 to 21, 2026, providing participants from agriculture, food processing, trading, exports and international business with practical inputs on entering and operating in global agri-food markets.
The programme combined classroom sessions, expert interactions, case studies and a field visit to JNPA.
T he Agri-Food EXIM course conducted The five-day Agri-Food export consignments.
Interactions with port by MCCIA covered the complete authorities provided exposure to shipping and EXIM course by MCCIA agri-food export process, beginning logistics and helped participants understand covered the export cycle with product and market selection and the sequence from sourcing and compliance extending to buyer identification, pricing, from product and market to documentation, transportation, port regulatory compliance, certifications, payment handling and final shipment.
selection to compliance, security, documentation, logistics and The course was aimed at farmers, finance, documentation, delivery to international markets.
Sessions Farmer Producer Organisations (FPOs), were structured around practical issues logistics and shipment.
food processors, entrepreneurs and trading encountered by businesses while preparing for businesses seeking to access international and executing export transactions.
markets.
Through a combination of technical phytosanitary requirements, the National Export Requirements Explained inputs and field exposure, AEFC sought Programme for Organic Production Participants were introduced to to improve participants’ preparedness in (NPOP) and other certifications, export global agri-export markets, methods for evaluating markets, meeting compliance documentation, logistics and supply-chain selecting products and target markets, buyer requirements, managing export risks and
management.
Case studies, interactive identification, export pricing and international engaging with international buyers.
discussions and question-and-answer sessions quality requirements.
Sessions also covered l were used to explain the practical implications traceability, certifications, documentation, and risks involved in these areas.
branding and digital marketing and their role JNPA Visit Provides Port Exposure in meeting overseas buyer requirements.
As part of the programme, participants Experts and guest speakers from different visited Jawaharlal Nehru Port Authority Scan the QR code to areas of the agri-food export ecosystem listen to the gist of the (JNPA) in Uran, near Mumbai to understand provided inputs on banking and export article.
port operations and the movement of finance, ECGC and payment-risk mitigation, 44 | SAMPADA | august 2026
This article is from Sampada, published by MCCIA.